{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.213492, "questionText": "What is COVID-19?", "answerText": "Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses. Some cause illness in people and others cause illness in animals. Human coronaviruses are common and are typically associated with mild illnesses, similar to the common cold. COVID-19 is a new disease that has not been previously identified in humans. Rarely, animal coronaviruses can infect people, and more rarely, these can then spread from person to person through close contact. There have been 2 other specific coronaviruses that have spread from animals to humans and which have caused severe illness in humans. These are the: \nsevere acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS CoV)\nMiddle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS CoV)", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf34b23a-7e7d-11ea-a2fe-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf34b35c-7e7d-11ea-873c-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf34b3ca-7e7d-11ea-8f11-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2142458, "questionText": "What are the risks of getting COVID-19?", "answerText": "COVID-19 is a serious health threat, and the situation is evolving daily. The risk will vary between and within communities, but given the increasing number of cases in Canada, the risk to Canadians is considered high. This does not mean that all Canadians will get the disease. It means that there is already a significant impact on our health care system. If we do not flatten the epidemic curve now, the increase of COVID-19 cases could impact health care resources available to Canadians. The risk for COVID-19 may be increased for certain settings such as: \ncruise ships\ncrowded areas (such as public transit and shopping centres)\ngatherings (spiritual and cultural settings, theatres, sports arenas, festivals and conferences)", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf34cf90-7e7d-11ea-a576-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf34d03a-7e7d-11ea-8380-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf34d09e-7e7d-11ea-8fd1-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.214856, "questionText": "How does COVID-19 spread?", "answerText": "Human coronaviruses cause infections of the nose, throat and lungs. They are most commonly spread from an infected person through: \nrespiratory droplets generated when you cough or sneeze\nclose, prolonged personal contact, such as touching or shaking hands\ntouching something with the virus on it, then touching your mouth, nose or eyes before washing your hands\n Current evidence suggests person-to-person spread is efficient when there is close contact.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf34e75a-7e7d-11ea-9eb2-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf34e7fa-7e7d-11ea-b950-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf34e854-7e7d-11ea-b908-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.21597, "questionText": "What is the incubation period for COVID-19?", "answerText": "Those who are infected with COVID-19 may have little to no symptoms. You may not know you have symptoms of COVID-19 because they are similar to a cold or flu. Symptoms have  included: \ncough\nfever\ndifficulty breathing\npneumonia in both lungs\n In severe cases, infection can lead  to death.  Symptoms may take up to 14 days to appear after exposure to COVID-19. This is the longest known incubation period for this disease.  Recent evidence indicates that the virus can be transmitted to others  from someone who is infected but not showing symptoms. This includes people  who:   \nhave not yet developed symptoms (pre-symptomatic)\nnever develop symptoms (asymptomatic)\n While experts know that these kinds of transmissions are happening among  those in close contact or in close physical settings, it is not known to what  extent. This means it is extremely important to follow the proven preventative measures.  Think you might have COVID-19?\nTake a self-assessment", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3512e8-7e7d-11ea-932c-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf351388-7e7d-11ea-a503-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3513e2-7e7d-11ea-90c0-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.216466, "questionText": "How many COVID-19 cases are there currently in Canada?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf352648-7e7d-11ea-8ae8-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3526de-7e7d-11ea-9e21-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf352738-7e7d-11ea-86bf-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.216821, "questionText": "Where can I find more details about the cases reported in Canada?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf353426-7e7d-11ea-82f9-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3534ba-7e7d-11ea-ae6f-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf353518-7e7d-11ea-980c-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2171872, "questionText": "Where can I get COVID-19 information specific to my province or territory?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf354274-7e7d-11ea-b79c-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf354330-7e7d-11ea-ba73-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf35438a-7e7d-11ea-9e67-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.21761, "questionText": "How can I make a difference in Canada’s COVID-19 response efforts?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3552f8-7e7d-11ea-930b-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3553ca-7e7d-11ea-9a25-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf35542e-7e7d-11ea-b387-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.218703, "questionText": "What are the symptoms of COVID-19?", "answerText": "Those who are infected with COVID-19 may have little to no symptoms. You may not know you have symptoms of COVID-19 because they are similar to a cold or flu. Symptoms have  included: \ncough\nfever\ndifficulty breathing\npneumonia in both lungs\n In severe cases, infection can lead  to death.  Symptoms may take up to 14 days to appear after exposure to COVID-19. This is the longest known incubation period for this disease.  Recent evidence indicates that the virus can be transmitted to others  from someone who is infected but not showing symptoms. This includes people  who:   \nhave not yet developed symptoms (pre-symptomatic)\nnever develop symptoms (asymptomatic)\n While experts know that these kinds of transmissions are happening among  those in close contact or in close physical settings, it is not known to what  extent. This means it is extremely important to follow the proven preventative measures.  Think you might have COVID-19?\nTake a self-assessment", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf357da8-7e7d-11ea-8c17-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf357e74-7e7d-11ea-9e0c-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf357ee8-7e7d-11ea-8732-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.219092, "questionText": "I think I might have COVID-19. Is there a self-assessment that I can do at home to help me determine if I need further care?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf358ce6-7e7d-11ea-add2-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf358d90-7e7d-11ea-8b9e-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf358de8-7e7d-11ea-bc03-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.221409, "questionText": "Can COVID-19 be transmitted when a person is not showing symptoms?", "answerText": "Those who are infected with COVID-19 may have little to no symptoms. You may not know you have symptoms of COVID-19 because they are similar to a cold or flu. Symptoms have  included: \ncough\nfever\ndifficulty breathing\npneumonia in both lungs\n In severe cases, infection can lead  to death.  Symptoms may take up to 14 days to appear after exposure to COVID-19. This is the longest known incubation period for this disease.  Recent evidence indicates that the virus can be transmitted to others  from someone who is infected but not showing symptoms. This includes people  who:   \nhave not yet developed symptoms (pre-symptomatic)\nnever develop symptoms (asymptomatic)\n While experts know that these kinds of transmissions are happening among  those in close contact or in close physical settings, it is not known to what  extent. This means it is extremely important to follow the proven preventative measures.  Think you might have COVID-19?\nTake a self-assessment", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf35e790-7e7d-11ea-8ca5-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf35e91e-7e7d-11ea-a16d-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf35e98c-7e7d-11ea-b868-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.222208, "questionText": "Is there a vaccine or therapy that can treat or prevent COVID-19?", "answerText": "Most people with mild coronavirus illness will recover on their own. If you are concerned about your symptoms, you should self-monitor and consult your health care provider. They may recommend steps you can take to relieve symptoms.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3606b4-7e7d-11ea-8803-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3607de-7e7d-11ea-ac1b-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf360892-7e7d-11ea-be39-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.222732, "questionText": "I am feeling stressed and overwhelmed. What can I do to care for my mental health?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf361b1e-7e7d-11ea-bcfb-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf361c06-7e7d-11ea-ae1b-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf361c62-7e7d-11ea-bddf-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2234108, "questionText": "What is my risk of getting COVID-19 in Canada?", "answerText": "COVID-19 is a serious health threat, and the situation is evolving daily. The risk will vary between and within communities, but given the increasing number of cases in Canada, the risk to Canadians is considered high. This does not mean that all Canadians will get the disease. It means that there is already a significant impact on our health care system. If we do not flatten the epidemic curve now, the increase of COVID-19 cases could impact health care resources available to Canadians.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf36359c-7e7d-11ea-a6e7-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3636be-7e7d-11ea-8cfb-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf36377a-7e7d-11ea-a751-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2241411, "questionText": "What is the difference between quarantine (self-isolate) and isolate?", "answerText": "There is a difference between advice to quarantine (self-isolate) and advice to isolate. It is important to note these measures are in place to protect the health and safety of Canadians.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf365228-7e7d-11ea-8975-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf36532e-7e7d-11ea-aacc-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf365392-7e7d-11ea-a6c6-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.224895, "questionText": "What is physical (social) distancing and how does it help to minimize COVID-19?", "answerText": "Together, we can slow the spread of COVID-19 by making a conscious effort to keep a physical distance between each other. Physical (social) distancing is proven to be one of the most effective ways to reduce the spread of illness during an outbreak. This means making changes in your everyday routines to minimize close contact with others, including: \navoiding crowded places and non-essential gatherings\navoiding common greetings, such as handshakes\nlimiting contact with people at higher risk like older adults and those in poor health\nkeeping a distance of at least 2 arms-length (approximately 2 metres) from others", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf366f9e-7e7d-11ea-8427-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf36708c-7e7d-11ea-9cd2-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3670fa-7e7d-11ea-a884-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.226232, "questionText": "I am told to stay at home as much as possible, but I do not have any symptoms nor have I travelled outside of Canada. Can I go outside?", "answerText": "Canadians should continue to think ahead about the actions that they can take to stay healthy and prevent the spread of COVID-19 in Canada. This includes staying at home as much as possible and being prepared in case you or a family member becomes ill. Everyone should be practising physical (social) distancing. Even if you do not have symptoms of COVID-19, you could become infected by others. As we continue to see transmission of the virus within different communities, we know that everyone must take precautions, even those who have not travelled outside of Canada. In an effort to prevent the spread of COVID-19 within communities and across the country, all Canadians are advised to: \nstay at home unless you have to go to work\r\n    \ntalk to your employer about working at home if possible\n\n\navoid all non-essential trips in your community\ndo not gather in groups\nlimit contact with people at higher risk, such as older adults and those in poor health\ngo outside to exercise but stay close to home\nif you leave your home, always keep a distance of at least 2 arms lengths (approximately 2 metres) from others\r\n    \nhousehold contacts (people you live with) do not need to distance from each other unless they are sick or have travelled in the last 14 days\n\n\n You can go for a walk if you: \nhave not been diagnosed with COVID-19\ndo not have symptoms of COVID-19\nhave not travelled outside of Canada in the past 14 days\n If you go out for a walk, do not congregate and always practise physical (social) distancing by keeping at least 2 metres apart from others at all times. Think you might have COVID-19?\nTake a self-assessment", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf36a3cc-7e7d-11ea-9568-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf36a4be-7e7d-11ea-b1fa-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf36a522-7e7d-11ea-9f17-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.22945, "questionText": "How can I protect myself from getting COVID-19?", "answerText": "Canadians should continue to think ahead about the actions that they can take to stay healthy and prevent the spread of COVID-19 in Canada. This includes staying at home as much as possible and being prepared in case you or a family member becomes ill. Everyone should be practising physical (social) distancing. Even if you do not have symptoms of COVID-19, you could become infected by others. As we continue to see transmission of the virus within different communities, we know that everyone must take precautions, even those who have not travelled outside of Canada. In an effort to prevent the spread of COVID-19 within communities and across the country, all Canadians are advised to: \nstay at home unless you have to go to work\r\n    \ntalk to your employer about working at home if possible\n\n\navoid all non-essential trips in your community\ndo not gather in groups\nlimit contact with people at higher risk, such as older adults and those in poor health\ngo outside to exercise but stay close to home\nif you leave your home, always keep a distance of at least 2 arms lengths (approximately 2 metres) from others\r\n    \nhousehold contacts (people you live with) do not need to distance from each other unless they are sick or have travelled in the last 14 days\n\n\n You can go for a walk if you: \nhave not been diagnosed with COVID-19\ndo not have symptoms of COVID-19\nhave not travelled outside of Canada in the past 14 days\n If you go out for a walk, do not congregate and always practise physical (social) distancing by keeping at least 2 metres apart from others at all times. Think you might have COVID-19?\nTake a self-assessment", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3721a8-7e7d-11ea-8ed3-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf37234c-7e7d-11ea-89fe-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3723ba-7e7d-11ea-8224-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.231522, "questionText": "Should the general population in Canada wear masks to protect themselves from COVID-19?", "answerText": "Medical masks, including surgical, medical procedure face masks and respirators (like N95 masks), must be kept for health care workers and others providing direct care to COVID-19 patients. Wearing a non-medical mask or face covering in the community has not been proven to protect the person wearing it. Strict hygiene and public health measures, including frequent hand washing and physical (social) distancing, will reduce your chance of being exposed to the virus. Wearing a non-medical mask or face covering is an additional measure you can take to protect others around you, even if you have no symptoms. It can be useful for short periods of time, when physical distancing is not possible in public settings such as when grocery shopping or using public transit. Wearing a non-medical mask or face covering covers your mouth and nose to help prevent your respiratory droplets from contaminating others or landing on surfaces. Just like our recommendation not to cough into your hands (instead, cover your cough with tissues or your sleeve), a mask can reduce the chance that others are coming into contact with your respiratory droplets. If wearing a non-medical mask or face covering makes you feel safer and stops you from touching your nose and mouth, that is also good. But remember not to touch or rub your eyes. Homemade cloth face coverings Use caution if you intend to wear a homemade cloth face covering. Instructions for sew and non-sew methods  are available.  Safety when wearing non-medical masks  It is important to understand that non-medical masks have limitations and need to be used safely. Non-medical masks or face coverings should not be placed on: \nchildren under age 2\nanyone who has trouble breathing\nanyone who is unconscious, incapacitated or otherwise unable to remove the mask without assistance\n If you choose to use a non-medical mask or face covering: \nyou must wash your hands immediately before putting it on and immediately after taking it off (in addition to practising good hand hygiene while wearing it)\nit should fit well (non-gaping)\nyou should not share it with others\n Face masks can become contaminated on the outside, or when touched by your hands. When wearing a mask or face covering, take the following precautions to protect yourself: \navoid touching it while using it\nchange a cloth mask as soon as it gets damp or soiled\r\n\t\t\nput it directly into the washing machine or a bag that can be emptied into the washing machine and then disposed of\ncloth masks and face coverings can be laundered with other items using a hot cycle, and then dried thoroughly\n\n\nnon-medical masks or face coverings that cannot be washed should be discarded and replaced as soon as they get damp, soiled or crumpled\r\n\t\t\ndispose of them properly in a lined garbage bin\ndo not discard them in shopping carts, on the ground, etc.\n\n\n Masks alone will not prevent the spread of COVID-19. You must consistently and strictly adhere to good hygiene and public health measures, including frequent hand washing and physical (social) distancing.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf37727a-7e7d-11ea-b152-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf37736c-7e7d-11ea-a977-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3773e4-7e7d-11ea-b3ea-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.232831, "questionText": "Is there a risk of contracting COVID-19 if I touch a surface that was potentially contaminated?", "answerText": "temperature\ntype of surface\nhumidity of the environment\n Surfaces frequently touched with hands are most likely to be contaminated, including: \ntables\nhandrails\ndoorknobs\nelectronics\ncountertops\nlight switches\nfaucet handles\ncabinet handles\nelevator buttons\n Products shipped within or from outside of Canada could also be contaminated. However, because parcels generally take days or weeks to be delivered, and are shipped at room temperature, the risk of spread is low. There is no known risk of coronaviruses entering Canada on parcels or packages. To protect yourself from COVID-19, make sure to do the following when handling products shipped within or outside of Canada: \nuse good hygiene measures\nregularly clean and disinfect surfaces\ndo not touch your eyes, nose and mouth", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf37a594-7e7d-11ea-8a82-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf37a63e-7e7d-11ea-bd47-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf37a6a2-7e7d-11ea-a0c0-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.233999, "questionText": "Are Canadians at risk for contracting COVID-19 if they receive a package or products shipped from other countries?", "answerText": "temperature\ntype of surface\nhumidity of the environment\n Surfaces frequently touched with hands are most likely to be contaminated, including: \ntables\nhandrails\ndoorknobs\nelectronics\ncountertops\nlight switches\nfaucet handles\ncabinet handles\nelevator buttons\n Products shipped within or from outside of Canada could also be contaminated. However, because parcels generally take days or weeks to be delivered, and are shipped at room temperature, the risk of spread is low. There is no known risk of coronaviruses entering Canada on parcels or packages. To protect yourself from COVID-19, make sure to do the following when handling products shipped within or outside of Canada: \nuse good hygiene measures\nregularly clean and disinfect surfaces\ndo not touch your eyes, nose and mouth", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf37d31e-7e7d-11ea-b6ea-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf37d3ca-7e7d-11ea-875a-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf37d424-7e7d-11ea-a811-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.235266, "questionText": "I am pregnant, am I at a greater risk for more serious outcomes related to COVID-19?", "answerText": "Because COVID-19 is a new disease, we are still learning how it affects pregnant women. At this time, there is no evidence to suggest that pregnant women are at a greater risk for more serious outcomes related to COVID-19 or that their developing child could be negatively affected by COVID-19. You can protect yourself from becoming ill by taking the following precautions: \nstay home as much as possible, except for important medical appointments\ntalk to your doctor, obstetrician or midwife about the possibility of telephone or videoconference appointments\navoid unnecessary visitors to your home\nwash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds\r\n    \nuse alcohol-based hand sanitizer if soap and water are not available\n\n\npractise physical distancing by keeping a distance of at least 2 metres from others\navoid touching your mouth, nose and eyes\navoid crowded places and peak-hours\nmake limited trips to the store for essentials\navoid travel by public transit\n For more information, refer to our advice for mothers  on pregnancy, childbirth and caring for newborns. If you are pregnant and concerned about COVID-19, speak to your health care provider.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3804a8-7e7d-11ea-876b-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf380566-7e7d-11ea-820e-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3807f0-7e7d-11ea-98f6-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.237089, "questionText": "Can COVID-19 be transmitted through food?", "answerText": "There is currently no evidence to suggest that food is a likely source or route of transmission of the virus and there are currently no reported cases of COVID 19 transmission through food. People are unlikely to be infected with the virus through food. Scientists and food safety authorities across the world are closely monitoring the spread of COVID-19. If we become aware of a potential food safety risk, appropriate actions will be taken to ensure the safety of Canada's food supply. Coronaviruses are killed by common cleaning and disinfection methods and by cooking food to safe internal temperatures. Learn more about food safety.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf384c10-7e7d-11ea-acc5-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf384d9e-7e7d-11ea-acaf-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf384e54-7e7d-11ea-a2c0-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.238485, "questionText": "Can my pet or other animals get sick from this virus?", "answerText": "The current spread of COVID-19 is a result of human-to-human transmission. There is no evidence to suggest that pets or other animals play a role in transmitting the disease to humans. Scientists are still trying to understand if and how it affects animals. Pets can contribute to our overall happiness and well-being, especially in times of stress. If you are feeling well (no symptoms of COVID-19) and are not self-isolating because of COVID-19 illness, you can continue to take walks with your dog or spend time with your pet. This can contribute to keeping both you and your pet healthy. As a precautionary measure, if you have COVID-19 symptoms or are self-isolating due to contact with a COVID-19 case, you should follow similar recommendations around animals, as you would around people in these circumstances: \navoid close contact with animals during your illness\r\n    \npractise good handwashing and avoid coughing and sneezing on your animals\ndo not visit farms or have contact with livestock\n\n\nif possible, have another member of your household care for your animals\r\n    \nif this is not possible, always wash your hands before and after touching animals, their food and supplies and practise good cough and sneezing etiquette\n\n\nlimit your animal's contact with other people and animals outside the household until your illness is resolved\n These measures are recommended as a precaution, and are basic practices to prevent transmission of diseases between humans and animals. If you have concerns, seek professional advice from your veterinarian or a public health professional who can help to answer your questions. The Canadian Food Inspection Agency website has more information about animals and COVID-19.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf388286-7e7d-11ea-a689-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf38837e-7e7d-11ea-b74d-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3883d8-7e7d-11ea-958b-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.23967, "questionText": "Are Canadians currently able to travel to the U.S.?", "answerText": "As of March 21, 2020, there is a 30-day restriction on all non-essential  travel at the Canada-U.S. border. Examples of non-essential travel include: \ntourism\nrecreation\nentertainment\n If you are healthy and must cross the border for work or other essential  purposes, you may continue to do so. Some examples of essential travel purposes  are: \nwork and study\ncritical infrastructure support\neconomic services and supply chains\nshopping for essential goods, such as:\r\n  \nmedication\nitems necessary for the health and safety of an individual or  family\n\nhealth, immediate medical care, safety and security\n These travellers will only be allowed into the country if they  have not been outside  Canada or the U.S. in the 14 days before requesting entry into Canada.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf38b0b0-7e7d-11ea-8ee4-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf38b16e-7e7d-11ea-a38e-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf38b1d2-7e7d-11ea-bb01-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2404082, "questionText": "I have recently returned from a trip outside of Canada and I have symptoms. What do I need to do?", "answerText": "If you are Canadian or a permanent resident, and you have symptoms  consistent with COVID-19, you may still  enter Canada by land, rail or sea. You may not enter Canada by air, to protect the health of all  travellers. If you have symptoms, you must isolate. This is mandatory. If required, immediate medical  attention will be provided upon arrival in Canada. Mandatory isolation means you must:", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf38cd86-7e7d-11ea-8ba6-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf38ce2e-7e7d-11ea-9849-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf38ce92-7e7d-11ea-82f5-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2410612, "questionText": "I have recently returned from a trip outside of Canada and I do not have any symptoms. What do I need to do?", "answerText": "If you have recently returned to Canada and you have no symptoms,  you must quarantine (self-isolate). This is mandatory. You  are at risk of developing symptoms and infecting others. Mandatory quarantine (self-isolate) means you must:", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf38e706-7e7d-11ea-8a86-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf38e79c-7e7d-11ea-bf31-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf38e800-7e7d-11ea-80ed-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2414248, "questionText": "I may have been exposed to COVID-19, but I am not sure. How do I know?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf38f53e-7e7d-11ea-9df1-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf38f5d4-7e7d-11ea-859e-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf38f62e-7e7d-11ea-b45e-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2422771, "questionText": "I have to travel for essential reasons. How can I reduce my risk of infection?", "answerText": "Take precautions against respiratory  illnesses,  and seek medical attention if you become sick. During your trip: \navoid large crowds or crowded areas\navoid contact with sick people, especially if they have a cough, fever or difficulty breathing\nbe aware of the local situation and follow local public health advice\nwash your hands often with soap under warm running water for at least 20 seconds\r\n  \nuse alcohol-based hand sanitizer  if soap and water are not available and always keep some with you when  you travel\n\npractise  proper cough  and sneeze etiquette", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf391686-7e7d-11ea-a4f6-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf391730-7e7d-11ea-95a0-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf39178a-7e7d-11ea-849c-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.247285, "questionText": "I am a Canadian travelling abroad and I need support. Who can I contact?", "answerText": "While the Government of Canada advises that you avoid all  non-essential travel outside of Canada, there may be times when travel is  essential.   You should expect increased health screening measures at points of entry  for international destinations, including airports and land borders. Local  authorities may impose control measures suddenly, including movement  restrictions such as quarantines. Some governments have implemented special entry and exit restrictions  for their territory. Before travelling, verify with the foreign diplomatic mission of your destination to see if  its authorities have implemented any specific restrictions related to this  situation. These include entry requirements, border closures and flight  suspensions. To ensure you are aware of the latest developments on this evolving  situation, we recommend: \nmonitoring the news\nreading all travel advice and advisories for your destination\n If you are in an affected destination, we recommend: \nfollowing the instructions of local authorities\nsigning up to our Registration of Canadians Abroad service to receive important updates to stay connected with the Government of Canada in case of an emergency abroad or an emergency at home\n If you are trying to return home and need financial assistance, the  Government of Canada has created the COVID-19 Emergency Loan Program for Canadians  Abroad. The program provides the option of an emergency loan to Canadians in  need of immediate financial assistance to return home or to temporarily cover  their life-sustaining needs while working toward their return. Global Affairs Canada is providing 24/7 consular support to Canadians  abroad affected by COVID-19 through:  \nthe  Emergency Watch and Response Centre \nconsular  staff at its network of missions", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf39da76-7e7d-11ea-baae-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf39dccc-7e7d-11ea-ae80-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf39dd6e-7e7d-11ea-b947-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.24804, "questionText": "I am a traveller trying to return home to Canada. How do I get financial support while abroad?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf39f7b8-7e7d-11ea-96cf-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf39f8b4-7e7d-11ea-a007-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf39f966-7e7d-11ea-81df-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.2485518, "questionText": "What        actions are being take by the Government of Canada to respond to the pandemic?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3a0ba4-7e7d-11ea-b21f-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3a0c4c-7e7d-11ea-9313-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3a0cd0-7e7d-11ea-8ec6-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.249804, "questionText": "What actions are being taken at Canadian borders to stop COVID-19 from entering Canada?", "answerText": "As of March 21, 2020, there is a 30-day restriction on all non-essential  travel at the Canada-U.S. border. Examples of non-essential travel include: \ntourism\nrecreation\nentertainment\n If you are healthy and must cross the border for work or other essential  purposes, you may continue to do so. Some examples of essential travel purposes  are: \nwork and study\ncritical infrastructure support\neconomic services and supply chains\nshopping for essential goods, such as:\r\n  \nmedication\nitems necessary for the health and safety of an individual or  family\n\nhealth, immediate medical care, safety and security\n These travellers will only be allowed into the country if they  have not been outside  Canada or the U.S. in the 14 days before requesting entry into Canada.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3a3c98-7e7d-11ea-ab8c-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3a3d86-7e7d-11ea-904d-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3a3e26-7e7d-11ea-8393-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.250283, "questionText": "How is Canada supporting its citizens and businesses as a result of the COVID-19 outbreak?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3a4f4c-7e7d-11ea-936c-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3a4ff6-7e7d-11ea-8465-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3a5050-7e7d-11ea-ad2a-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.251214, "questionText": "How is Canada monitoring the supply of drug and medical devices to ensure that there are no shortages?", "answerText": "The Government of Canada is actively monitoring the novel COVID-19 and its impact on the supply of prescription and over-the-counter drugs, natural health products and medical devices in Canada. We do this through regular contact with:  \ndrug, medical device and natural health products manufacturers and importers\n provincial, territorial and international partners\n We are aware that there may be supply disruptions related to COVID-19 and are monitoring the situation closely. Companies that market prescription drugs for human use in Canada must report anticipated or actual drug shortages on Drug Shortages Canada. We have contacted companies to remind them of this requirement. Industry stakeholder associations have also been asked to notify us of any early signals of shortages related to COVID-19. Drug and medical device shortage signals can also be reported by the provinces and territories, healthcare professionals or the public.  We will continue to use all available tools to help manage critical national shortages when they happen, and work with partners so that Canadians have access to the medications they need. Learn more about drug shortages in Canada.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3a73b4-7e7d-11ea-abe5-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3a74d8-7e7d-11ea-af2a-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3a7562-7e7d-11ea-91df-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.256574, "questionText": "What actions can my family and I take to protect against COVID-19?", "answerText": "Canadians should continue to think ahead about the actions that they can take to stay healthy and prevent the spread of any illness, especially respiratory infections. Now and always during cold and flu season, stay home if you are sick. Encourage those you know are sick to stay home until they no longer have symptoms. Since respiratory viruses, such as the one that causes COVID-19, are spread through contact, change how you greet one another. Instead of a handshake, a kiss or a hug, a friendly wave or elbow bump is less likely to expose you to respiratory viruses. Practise frequent hygiene, which includes proper hand washing and coughing and sneezing etiquette. Clean and disinfect frequently touched objects and surfaces, such as toys and door handles. These are the most important ways that you can protect yourself and your family from respiratory illness, including COVID-19. \nMake a plan\nIf COVID-19 becomes common in your community, you will want to have thought about how to change your behaviours and routines to reduce the risk of infection.\nYour plan should include how you can change your regular habits to reduce your exposure to crowded places. For example, you may:\n\ndo your grocery shopping at off-peak hours\ncommute by public transit outside of the busy rush hour\nopt to exercise outdoors instead of in an indoor fitness class\n\nYour plan should also include what you will do if you become sick. If you are a caregiver of children or other dependents, you will want to have thought ahead to engage backup caregivers.\nYou should also think about what you will do if a member of your family becomes sick and needs care. Talk to your employer about working from home if you are needed to care for a family member at home.\nIf you become ill, stay home until you are no longer showing symptoms. Employers should not require a sick leave note as that will put added pressure on limited health care services.\nYour plan should include shopping for supplies that you should have on hand at all times. This will ensure you do not need to leave your home while you are sick or busy caring for an ill family member.\nYour plan should build on the kits you have prepared for other potential emergencies. For more information on how to prepare yourself and your family in the event of an emergency, please visit GetPrepared.ca.\n \nFill your prescriptions\nRefill your prescriptions now so that you do not have to go to a busy pharmacy if you do become sick. Consider seeing your health care provider to renew your prescriptions ahead of time.\n \nStock up on essentials but avoid panic buying\nAt this time, it makes sense to fill your cupboards with non-perishable food items, so that you do not need to go shopping if you become sick.\nIt is easier on the supply chain if people gradually build up their household stores instead of making large-scale purchases all at once. To do this, you can add a few extra items to your grocery cart every time you shop. Good options are easy-to-prepare foods like:\n\ndried pasta and sauce\nprepared canned soups\ncanned vegetables and beans\n\nIt is also a good idea to have extra stores of:\n\npet food\ntoilet paper\nfacial tissue\nfeminine hygiene products\ndiapers (if you have children who use them)\n\nThe reason for stocking up on these items is not necessarily because you will need to self-isolate. Having these supplies on hand will ensure you do not need to leave your home at the peak of the outbreak or if you become ill.\n \nHow to care for those who are ill\nIf you or a member of your family become ill with COVID-19, there are precautions that should be taken in the home. Your health care provider will advise you if hospital care is more appropriate. \nChildren who have mild COVID-19 symptoms are able to stay at home with a caregiver throughout their recovery without needing hospitalization. If you are caring for a child who has suspected or probable COVID-19, it is important to follow the advice for caregivers. This advice will help you protect yourself, others in your home, as well as others in the community.\nTo prepare for these potential situations, you should have on hand:\n\nsoap\nfacial tissue\npaper towels\nalcohol-based hand sanitizer\nhousehold cleaning products\nregular detergents for washing dishes and doing laundry\nfever-reducing medications, such as acetaminophen or ibuprofen\r\n      \nthis includes products for children if you are a parent or caregiver\n\n\nplastic garbage bags for containing soiled tissues and other waste\ndiluted bleach, prepared according to the instructions on the label, or in a ratio of 1 teaspoon (5 mL) per cup (250 mL)\r\n      \nthis assumes bleach is 5% sodium hypochlorite, to give a 0.1% sodium hypochlorite solution\n\n\n\n \nGet reliable information\nMake sure that you get high-quality information about COVID-19 from reliable sources. The Public Health Agency of Canada is a reliable source of information, as are provincial and territorial public health authorities.\nIf you are finding that the news media is making you feel anxious, take a break from it.\n \nCommunicate with family, friends and neighbours\nLet your family, friends and neighbours know that you are making plans to prepare for COVID-19. Share your plan with them, as this might motivate them to make their own.\nTalk to them about a buddy system in which you agree to check in on each other and run essential errands if you become sick.\nThink about the type of care you would want if you became seriously ill, and talk to family, health care providers or others who would be making decisions about your care if you were not able to do so.  These discussions can help caregivers feel more comfortable and confident in making decisions aligned with your wishes. \nIt’s not always easy; some need help to  begin these difficult conversations. Visit advance care planning for information, tools, and prompts to  help with starting these conversations.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3b451e-7e7d-11ea-99ab-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3b464a-7e7d-11ea-9b14-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3b46c2-7e7d-11ea-a55d-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.257115, "questionText": "How do I care for a person with COVID-19 at home?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3b5a2c-7e7d-11ea-8a7f-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3b5ad8-7e7d-11ea-a3e0-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3b5b3a-7e7d-11ea-b6e6-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.257492, "questionText": "I am essential employee, what can I do to protect myself while on the job?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3b68fa-7e7d-11ea-80ba-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3b69b8-7e7d-11ea-a24f-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3b6a1c-7e7d-11ea-8927-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.257864, "questionText": "I have a child with COVID-19. What steps do I need to take to protect myself and others in the home?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3b7764-7e7d-11ea-a118-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3b77fa-7e7d-11ea-b99a-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3b7854-7e7d-11ea-b9ee-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.261893, "questionText": "As an employee, what role do I play in reducing the spread of infection?", "answerText": "Across Canada, we are changing the way we work to prevent the spread of COVID-19. For some workplaces, this may mean changing hours of operation, closing for a period of time or working from home. Others continue to go to work because their jobs are essential to keeping Canada functioning during this outbreak.  Essential workers are considered critical to preserving life, health and basic societal functioning. This includes, but is not limited to: \nfirst responders\nhealth care workers\nhydro and natural gas\ncritical infrastructure workers\nworkers who are essential for supplying society with critical goods such as food and medicines\n All employees should understand and comply with the infection prevention policies and practices in place in their workplaces. Employers should use the risk-informed decision-making guidelines for workplaces and businesses during the COVID-19 pandemic.  Employers and employees will need to work together to protect their own health and their clients’ health, as well as deliver essential services.  \nGeneral advice\n\nIncrease awareness about COVID-19 through communication with staff. \nEvaluate the workplace for areas where people have frequent contact with each other and shared objects.\nIncrease the distance between desks and workstations as well as employees and customers (ideally 2 metres).\r\n      \nA physical barrier like a cubicle or Plexiglas window also works to increase distance between people. \n\n\n\nMore information is available related to COVID-19 in the workplace for employers, employees and essential service workers (including work-related travel). \n \nHygiene\n\nEncourage frequent hand washing, sneeze and cough etiquette, and staying home when ill.\r\n      \nIf COVID-19 symptoms develop, the employee should immediately be isolated from others and sent home without using public transit, if possible.\n\n\nEnsure frequent cleaning and disinfecting, with particular attention to high-touch surfaces, such as:\r\n      \nbars\ndesks\nphones\nkitchens\ncomputers\ncash registers\nelevator buttons\nrestaurant tables and menus\n\n\nProvide access to handwashing areas and place hand sanitizers in prominent locations throughout the workplace, if possible.\n\n \nFlexible work arrangements and sick leave\n\nWhere feasible, adjust policies to reduce social contact, such as:\r\n      \nflexible hours\nstaggering start times\nteleworking arrangements\nusing email and teleconferencing\n\n\nRelax sick leave policies to support employees in staying home when ill or monitoring symptoms.\r\n      \nThis includes suspending the need for medical notes to reduce the burden on an already stressed health care system.\n\n\nPrepare for increases in absenteeism due to illness among employees and their families or possibly school closures.\r\n      \nAccess your business continuity plan for how to maintain key business functions if faced with high absenteeism.\nConsider the need for cross-training personnel to function in key positions.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3c1502-7e7d-11ea-898d-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3c16b0-7e7d-11ea-9516-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3c1818-7e7d-11ea-9813-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.262468, "questionText": "As an employer, how do I implement appropriate public health measures to prevent and reduce the spread of COVID-19 in the workplace?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3c2b3a-7e7d-11ea-b811-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3c2be6-7e7d-11ea-be8c-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3c2c40-7e7d-11ea-b372-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/coronavirus-disease-covid-19.html#faq", "sourceName": "Public Health Agency of Canada", "sourceDate": 1586876400.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586876400.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": false, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586888913.262839, "questionText": "Are small gatherings still allowed to take place?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "bf3c39cc-7e7d-11ea-b614-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "bf3c3a6e-7e7d-11ea-a835-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "bf3c3ac8-7e7d-11ea-94b5-8c85901aafa7", "topic": ""}
